+447554153196 kimonas.tsiliras@gmail.com https://kimonastsiliras.com/

Profile

Artificial Intelligence MSc student at King's College London. Motivated in solving difficult problems via creative and analytical thinking. Successfully completed multiple challenging IT projects at university and within the industry using areas of expertise below. Sensitive to different cultures, team leader and team player establishing and fostering strong relationships among team members. Strong ability to adapt and evolve in a changing and challenging environment.

Areas of Expertise

- Machine Learning
- Computer Vision
- Software Engineering
- Database Management

- Data Analytics
- Data Structures
- Web Development
- Digital Animation

Education

Kings College London | MSc Artificial Intelligence

London, UK | Sep 2023 - Aug 2024

<u>Modules</u>: Pattern Recognition, Neural Networks and Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Data Mining, Al reasoning and decision making, Biologically Inspired Methods, Distributed Ledgers and Cryptocurrencies, Agents and Multiagent Systems, Human Computer Interaction.

<u>Dissertation (in progress):</u> Utilising Conformal Prediction methods in Python to enhance Uncertainty Quantification in Breast Cancer Classification model predictions

University of Exeter | BSc Computer Science

Exeter, UK | Sep 2020 – Jun 2023

GPA: 67.54% (Upper 2:1), <u>Key Modules</u>: AI & Applications, Learning from Data, Data Structures & Algorithms, Nature Inspired Computation, Software Development, Database Theory & Design, Computational Mathematics, Enterprise Computing, Object-Oriented Programming, Web Development.

<u>Final Year Project:</u> Developed a Machine Learning Python model for skin lesion classification as benign or as melanomas retrieving images from a large database. Used the Keras and TensorFlow modules to build and train three CNN architectures, ResNet50, DenseNet121 and Xception by integrating pre-trained Imagenet layers and a custom classification layer to identify the best performing CNN.

<u>Key Software Engineering Group Project</u>: Developed a web application game for students to explore Exeter University's campus. The objective was to engage users by challenging them with university related questions to unlock various incentives. HTML, CSS with Bootstrap styles and Javascript were used for frontend and Python Django for backend.

Work Experience

OTE - Deutsche Telekom Group | Full Stack Development Intern Athens, Greece | Jun 2023 – Jul 2023

- Co-developed an Al-powered application to expedite the processing of job candidates' CVs using OpenAl's Embeddings database and GPT-4. Used Vue JS to develop the application's frontend.
- Expanded my Python Flask expertise by effectively handling HTTP requests and responses in JSON format, managing session variables and building database models.

Accenture | Application Development Associate Intern

Athens, Greece | Jun 2022 - Jul 2022

- Collaborated with the software development team on enhancing the largest Greek bank's website by developing new functionalities for client use.
- Used the Angular framework to build features for microloan applications and business bank account opening.

Exeter, UK | Oct 2021 - May 2022

• ExCode Program: Taught Python fundamentals to Exeter University students from diverse academic backgrounds, guiding them in acquiring coding skills.

Ernst & Young | Frontend Development Intern

Athens, Greece | Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

- Collaborated with the Data & Analytics team to develop an Angular web application to manage and keep record of accounting and actuarial data, audit trails, as well as security and error logs for a large insurance company.
- · Used the Git version control system for source code management and branching.

OTE - Deutsche Telekom Group | Data Science Intern

Athens, Greece | Jun 2020 - Jul 2020

- Analysed the customer attributes with the greatest influence on customer churn and on switching to alternative telecom operators. Results contributed to the marketing team's consumer campaigns.
- Used Python pandas for data processing and matplotlib for data visualization and statistics.

Technical Proficiency / Additional Skills - Engagements

IT Languages and Frameworks: Python, MySQL, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Bootstrap, Typescript, PHP, Go, C/C++, Vue, React

Languages: Greek (native), English (C2 Proficiency), French (Delf B2), Italian (B1 level), Spanish (A2 level) Volunteering at the largest Greek NGO "Smile of the Child". Piano Player (reached ABRSM grade 6). Basketball Team Player (various teams in Greece and UK). Judo (Green Belt)